
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><description>4chan.org's Official Blog</description><title>4chan Blog</title><generator>Tumblr (3.0; @4chan)</generator><link>http://blog.4chan.org/</link>



<item><title>I&amp;#8217;m retiring after serving as 4chan&amp;#8217;s founder and administrator for more than 11 years,...</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m retiring after serving as 4chan&amp;#8217;s founder and administrator for more than 11 years, from the age of 15. You can read the full announcement on the &lt;a href="https://www.4chan.org/news" title="4chan - News - THE NEXT CHAPTER" target="_blank"&gt;4chan News page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/108740766397</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/108740766397</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 11:05:37 -0500</pubDate><category>4chan</category><category>moot</category><category>retirement</category><category>mootxico</category><category>goodnight sweet prince</category></item>


<item><title>New requirement for 4chan volunteers going forward</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently we introduced a new requirement for 4chan&amp;#8217;s volunteer moderators and janitors, which is that they sign a volunteer agreement that puts in writing a number of things that have always been true, namely that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Moderating 4chan is a volunteer position and not a real &amp;#8220;job&amp;#8221; in any sense of the word (yes, they truly do it &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="greentext"&gt;&amp;gt;for free&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;), however we expect volunteers to conduct themselves in a professional manner and in accordance with the moderation guidelines and training we provide.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Volunteers are expected to hold in confidence any and all private information they come into contact with, especially regarding our users, and they are not to use or disseminate that information except to perform their volunteer duties.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In addition to signing this formal agreement, we now require proof of identity from all volunteers, present and future. Why? So we can enforce the agreement should it be violated (ie. user information being misused, leaks, etc) and establish a liability barrier in between the company and its volunteers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most large websites with analogous volunteer roles use similar agreements, and we were long overdue for one of our own. You can find a full copy of the agreement below (note this will be mandatory as of our next &lt;a href="https://www.4chan.org/janitorapp" title="4chan - Janitor Application" target="_blank"&gt;janitor drive&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4chan, LLC&lt;br/&gt;Volunteer Moderator Agreement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are the agreed-upon terms pursuant to which you will be volunteering with 4chan, LLC (&amp;#8220;4chan&amp;#8221;) as a Volunteer Moderator:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Duties. &lt;/strong&gt;This is a volunteer position. As a Volunteer Moderator, you will monitor user-posted content on 4chan&amp;#8217;s website at 4chan.org, including its subdomains and associated domains and any message boards contained thereon (collectively, the &amp;#8220;Website&amp;#8221;), and (a) report, edit, and/or remove user-posted content that is in violation of the Rules posted at &lt;a href="https://www.4chan.org/rules" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.4chan.org/rules&lt;/a&gt; (&amp;#8220;Prohibited Content&amp;#8221;) and (b) block users from accessing the Website for posting Prohibited Content (collectively, the &amp;#8220;Moderation Duties&amp;#8221;). You will perform the Moderation Duties in accordance with this letter agreement and any instructions and guidelines for Volunteer Moderators provided by 4chan to you from time-to-time. By entering into this letter agreement and performing the Moderation Duties, you represent and warrant that (x) you have no contractual commitments or other legal obligations that would prohibit your activities in connection with 4chan, (y) you will perform the Moderation Duties in a good and professional manner, and (z) you have full power, right and authority to enter into this letter agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Relationship; No Compensation. &lt;/strong&gt;You understand and agree that this is an unpaid, volunteer position and not an employment relationship. This position is for no specific period of time and will be &amp;#8220;at will,&amp;#8221; meaning that either you or 4chan may terminate your position and the service relationship at any time and for any reason, with or without cause. Although you must perform the Moderation Duties in accordance with all terms and conditions contained in this letter agreement, or as otherwise provided by 4chan to you, 4chan does not require any specific time commitment for this position (i.e. it is not &amp;#8220;full time&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;part time&amp;#8221;), and the amount of time you spend performing the Moderation Duties is solely at your own discretion. You acknowledge and agree that 4chan will not pay you any wages or other compensation (including without limitation any equity or ownership share in 4chan) at any time, now or in the future, under any circumstances, for performing the Moderation Duties, and you will not be eligible to participate in any 4chan company-sponsored benefits. Any contrary representations that may have been made to you are superseded by this letter agreement. 4chan may terminate your position and the service relationship with or without notice to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Identity Verification. &lt;/strong&gt;Your service with 4chan is contingent upon your providing legal proof of your identity and your representation hereunder that you are authorized to work for 4chan. Prior to starting the Moderation Duties, you must provide 4chan with a copy of a government-issued identification document (e.g. a passport or driver&amp;#8217;s license) in a form reasonably acceptable to 4chan. You represent and warrant that all information you provide regarding your identity and ability to perform the Moderation Duties, including but not limited to any form of identification you provide, is valid, accurate and up-to-date. You acknowledge that providing 4chan with any false or inaccurate information regarding your identity is both a breach of this contract and a punishable offense under law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Proprietary Information. &lt;/strong&gt;You acknowledge that in the course of performing the Moderation Duties, you may encounter or otherwise gain access to certain Proprietary Information of 4chan, and you agree to hold in confidence and not disclose to any third parties in any manner or medium whatsoever or, except in performing the Moderation Duties, use any Proprietary Information. &amp;#8220;Proprietary Information&amp;#8221; means all financial, business, legal and technical information of 4chan or any of its affiliates, suppliers, customers, users, contractors, owners, and employees (including without limitation information about user-posted content, personally identifiable information pertaining to users (such as but not limited to IP addresses, location, and cookie data), team member identities or nicknames (including without limitation other moderators, and regardless of whether such identities or nicknames are real-life or virtual), chat logs, orientation materials, legal or regulatory affairs, operations, marketing, transactions, inventions, processes, materials, data, know-how and ideas, whether tangible or intangible, and including all copies and other derivatives thereof), that is previously, presently or subsequently disclosed by or for 4chan to you or which is otherwise made available to you or which you learn in the course of performing the Moderation Duties. For the avoidance of doubt, this letter agreement, its terms, and its existence shall constitute 4chan&amp;#8217;s Proprietary Information. Upon termination or as otherwise requested by 4chan, you will promptly return to 4chan all items and copies containing or embodying Proprietary Information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Survival. &lt;/strong&gt;Your obligations under Sections 4, 5 and 6 of this letter agreement shall survive any termination or expiration of this letter agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Miscellaneous. &lt;/strong&gt;This letter agreement constitutes the entire agreement, and supersedes all prior negotiations, understandings or agreements (oral or written), between the parties concerning the subject matter hereof. No change, consent or waiver to this letter agreement will be effective unless in writing and signed by the party against which enforcement is sought. The failure of 4chan to enforce its rights under this letter agreement at any time for any period shall not be construed as a waiver of such rights. Unless expressly provided otherwise, each right and remedy in this letter agreement is in addition to any other right or remedy, at law or in equity, and the exercise of one right or remedy will not be deemed a waiver of any other right or remedy. In the event that any provision of this letter agreement shall be determined to be illegal or unenforceable, that provision will be limited or eliminated to the minimum extent necessary so that letter agreement shall otherwise remain in full force and effect and enforceable. This letter agreement shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the State of New York, USA without regard to the conflicts of laws provisions thereof. Exclusive jurisdiction and venue for any action arising under this letter agreement is in the federal and state courts located in New York City, and both parties hereby consent to such jurisdiction and venue for this purpose. Any notice hereunder will be effective upon receipt and shall be given in writing, in English and delivered to the other party in a manner indicated by 4chan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for any future leaks that may inevitably occur—frankly, I look forward to them. I&amp;#8217;ve been amused by past leaks because they usually show just how &lt;a href="http://s.4cdn.org/image/news/jscreenshot.png" title="/j/ Screenshot" target="_blank"&gt;mundane and even-keeled&lt;/a&gt; 4chan&amp;#8217;s moderation team is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t communicate this nearly often enough, but I am deeply grateful to our team of dedicated volunteers. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/108414215167</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/108414215167</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:07:00 -0500</pubDate><category>4chan</category><category>moderator</category><category>janitor</category></item><item><title>The future of 4chan Pass</title><description>&lt;p&gt;As many of you know, &lt;a href="http://blog.4chan.org/post/104874516062/no-captcha-recaptcha" title="4chan Blog - No CAPTCHA reCAPTCHA" target="_blank"&gt;last week we upgraded&lt;/a&gt; to the new reCAPTCHA API, bringing CAPTCHA-less posting to the masses &lt;span class="greentext"&gt;&amp;gt;for free&lt;/span&gt;. Since the upgrade, approximately 25-30% of daily solve attempts encounter no CAPTCHA at all, with failure rates hovering at an all-time low of 6%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside the new CAPTCHA, we temporarily disabled the sale of &lt;a href="http://4chan%20-%204chan%20Pass" title="https://www.4chan.org/pass" target="_blank"&gt;4chan Passes&lt;/a&gt; as we evaluated whether or not to continue supporting them in light of the change. Ultimately, we decided to resume offering 4chan Passes for sale for those who don&amp;#8217;t want to deal with CAPTCHA at all, would like to post from behind a blocked IP range, or just plain want to support the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve also decided to offer a limited time, pro-rated refund to those who currently hold an active 4chan Pass that was purchased on or before December 8th, 2014. While we don&amp;#8217;t normally offer refunds for Pass purchases, we felt it was best to provide an opportunity for users who feel their Pass has been devalued as a result of the CAPTCHA change to request a pro-rated refund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 4chan relies primarily on Pass sales to make ends meet, we&amp;#8217;ll continue to sell and support them for the foreseeable future, and may consider adding additional features at a later date and time (&lt;a href="mailto:moot@4chan.org?subject=4chan%20Pass%20Ideas" target="_blank"&gt;ideas welcome&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;d like to submit a refund request for your active 4chan Pass that was purchased on or before December 8th, please visit &lt;strike&gt;this link&lt;/strike&gt; and follow the instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks as always to our Pass holders for their support—it is greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/105401274532</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/105401274532</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 21:01:00 -0500</pubDate><category>4chan</category><category>4chan pass</category><category>captcha</category></item><item><title>No CAPTCHA reCAPTCHA</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Two days ago, we upgraded to the new reCAPTCHA API, dubbed the &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://googleonlinesecurity.blogspot.com/2014/12/are-you-robot-introducing-no-captcha.html" title="Google Online Security Blog - Are you a robot? Introducing “No CAPTCHA reCAPTCHA”" target="_blank"&gt;No CAPTCHA reCAPTCHA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new API allows users determined to not be spambots to bypass typing a verification, giving them a CAPTCHA-less posting experience. Below you can see the change from our last full day using the old version of the API to our first full day using the new version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://31.media.tumblr.com/6941af3ffd14baf55b25f7cde5c970d7/tumblr_inline_ngdze93Mlt1r2vq4m.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 7th, 90% of solve attempts resulted in a pass, and 10% resulted in a fail. On December 9th, the first full day of the new version, &lt;strong&gt;30% of solve attempts encountered no CAPTCHA at all&lt;/strong&gt;, with the remainder being 64% pass and 6% fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We understand there have been a few hiccups for users using third-party extensions and unofficial apps, however we expect them to be updated soon. We hope that as reCAPTCHA tweaks their algorithm over time, more users will be able to take advantage of the CAPTCHA-less posting experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/104874516062</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/104874516062</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 17:40:42 -0500</pubDate><category>4chan</category><category>captcha</category><category>recaptcha</category></item><item><title>Mobile site improvements and change to moderation</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The mobile site has received a slew of updates recently, including:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;The ability to view original filenames and truncated names/subjects (tap the file size or inline expand the image; tap truncated text to expand).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Support for infinite scroll (tap &amp;#8220;Load More&amp;#8221; at the bottom of board indexes, or check &amp;#8220;Always use infinite scroll&amp;#8221; in Settings).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;A dark theme (Tomorrow) for nighttime browsing, enabled in Settings under &amp;#8220;Miscellaneous.&amp;#8221;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Top navigation now auto-hides upon scrolling down to free up vertical space for reading threads. Scroll up to have it reappear.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Support for Thread Stats, with more native extension features to be enabled in the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Minor usability tweaks and visual polish.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the mobile updates, we&amp;#8217;ve also added the ability for janitors to submit warning requests as opposed to only ban requests, with the hope that it will reduce the number of bans issued for minor or borderline rule infractions. You can read the e-mail sent to janitors and moderators notifying them of the change below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll notice the Ban Request panel now has a checkbox to reduce the ban request to a warning. When &amp;#8220;Warn&amp;#8221; is checked, the post will still be deleted, but the poster will not be temporarily muted, and if the request is approved by a moderator a warning will be issued instead of a ban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the minor infractions we regularly issue bans for simply aren&amp;#8217;t worth blocking someone from posting for 24 to 72 hours. Granted, these are the most lenient ban lengths we&amp;#8217;ve had in all of our 11 years &amp;#8212; not to mention you once couldn&amp;#8217;t browse while banned! &amp;#8212; but banning for trivial infractions frustrates the userbase and ultimately discourages rule adherence, encourages ban evasion, and breeds ill will. Posters, lurkers, volunteers, and the site as a whole are harmed in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, we do not want warnings to be used as a replacement for regular deletions. Think of a warn request as a step &lt;em&gt;down&lt;/em&gt; from a ban, and &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a step &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt; from a deletion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples where you may want to request warnings instead of bans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;"Quality of Posts" and "Garbage Outside of /b/" issues (ex. "holds up spork my name is katy but u can call me t3h PeNgU1N oF d00m!"), ASCII macros, huge lists of quoted post numbers, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;People using avatars or signatures.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;Recommendation threads on /a/.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that not all ban request templates can be downgraded to a warn request (ex. Global Rule 1), and the checkbox will be greyed out and unusable in such cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strive for 4chan&amp;#8217;s moderation to be fair and consistent, and hope that posters will choose to respect the rules instead of deliberately breaking them in response to what is sometimes perceived as disproportionate punishment for minor or borderline infractions. Warnings and bans should only be used in cases where a rule has clearly been broken. Keep in mind that we publicly display a sampling of recently issued warnings/bans, and ideally the reasoning behind everything displayed should be easily understood by the person viewing it. If the text of the rule clearly fits the associated warned/banned post as it should, then there won&amp;#8217;t be confusion as to why action was taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janitors and moderators have always had the challenging task of walking a fine line and pleasing the insatiable masses. In a given month, more than 20 million people will browse 4chan, and upwards of 2 million will post. While catering to the individual tastes and opinions of millions of people isn&amp;#8217;t feasible, we owe it to ourselves as users to enforce the rules as objectively and consistently as possible in order to preserve the best possible site experience for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks as always for your volunteering and continued service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; —moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/103155892537</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/103155892537</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 18:18:50 -0500</pubDate><category>4chan</category><category>mobile</category><category>moderation</category></item><item><title>Enhanced Thread Watcher, unique posters, and delayed pruning</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Three new features, and a belated announcement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Thread Watcher can now auto-watch threads based on filters you&amp;#8217;ve set in the &amp;#8220;Filters &amp;amp; Highlights&amp;#8221; menu. It works by fetching catalog JSON and matching filters against OPs on the specified board(s). Note that auto-watching only works when you select individual boards for a filter (&amp;#8220;Boards&amp;#8221; can&amp;#8217;t be blank) and manually refresh the Thread Watcher, due to client-side CPU/bandwidth concerns (we may add a user specifiable timer in the future).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threads now display the number of unique posters in a thread (based on IP). We&amp;#8217;re trialling this as a way to give users an idea of how many active contributors there are in a given thread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delayed pruning was expanded to all boards except for /b/ some weeks ago. Per the &lt;a href="http://blog.4chan.org/post/94542880437/sayonara-e-mail-field-and-delayed-thread-pruning" title="4chan Blog - Sayonara E-mail field, and delayed thread pruning" target="_blank"&gt;original announcement&lt;/a&gt;, once a thread expires it is retained for a period of 48 hours before being pruned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/102200648492</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/102200648492</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 13:39:39 -0500</pubDate><category>4chan</category></item><item><title>Sayonara E-mail field, and delayed thread pruning</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Today we&amp;#8217;re making two noteworthy changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The E-mail field has been replaced with Options.&lt;/strong&gt; This field had mainly been used for posting options such as sage and dice-rolling. If a user wishes to provide contact information, they can do so in the Comment field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We&amp;#8217;re &lt;strong&gt;trialling&lt;/strong&gt; delayed thread pruning on specific boards.&lt;/strong&gt; While not a true archive, threads on /a/ and /v/ will continue to be accessible for a period of 48 hours after being pushed off of the board index. We may roll this out to additional worksafe (blue) boards in the future, as well as increase or reduce the retention period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/94542880437</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/94542880437</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 12:25:00 -0400</pubDate><category>4chan</category></item><item><title>IPv6 support for 4chan</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Today we&amp;#8217;re pleased to announce support for IPv6 on all of 4chan&amp;#8217;s domains, thanks to &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com" title="CloudFlare" target="_blank"&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt;'s new &lt;a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/eliminating-the-last-reasons-to-not-enable-ipv6" title="Eliminating the last reasons to not enable IPv6 | CloudFlare Blog" target="_blank"&gt;Pseudo IPv4&lt;/a&gt; feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CloudFlare&amp;#8217;s CEO, Matthew Prince, goes into more detail on &lt;a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com" title="CloudFlare Blog" target="_blank"&gt;their blog&lt;/a&gt;, but essentially they&amp;#8217;ll accept traffic from our users over IPv6-enabled networks and route the request to our backend using plain ol&amp;#8217; IPv4. This removes the need for our application to be updated to natively support IPv6 (something we&amp;#8217;re working on, but is a ways off).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since IPv6&amp;#8217;s address space is considerably larger than IPv4, the mapping of IPs won&amp;#8217;t be one-to-one, however they believe it&amp;#8217;s large enough to accommodate the transition period between now and applications having true IPv6 support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re using an IPv6-enabled network you may see a slight performance benefit should your ISP have better routes to CloudFlare&amp;#8217;s datacenters that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; This change was reverted due to issues with our ban system, however our static content hosted at 4cdn.org is still accessible via IPv6 networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/87993160342</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/87993160342</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 11:47:00 -0400</pubDate><category>4chan</category><category>cloudflare</category><category>ipv6</category></item><item><title>Announcing 4chan's Vulnerability Disclosure Program</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In response to &lt;a href="http://blog.4chan.org/post/84289353232/concerning-a-recent-intrusion" title="4chan Blog - Concerning a recent intrusion" target="_blank"&gt;last month&amp;#8217;s intrusion&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;#8217;ve put numerous additional security measures in place in an effort to mitigate and prevent future intrusions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re also pleased to announce the creation of 4chan&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="https://www.4chan.org/security" target="_blank"&gt;Vulnerability Disclosure Program&lt;/a&gt;—commonly known as a &amp;#8220;bug bounty.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that by providing an officially sanctioned way for security researchers to submit security-related bugs, we&amp;#8217;ll be in a better position to detect and respond to vulnerabilities that may impact the site and its users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security remains an ongoing priority and commitment of ours. Thanks again for bearing with us, and sorry to anyone we&amp;#8217;ve let down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/84931784192</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/84931784192</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 12:22:38 -0400</pubDate><category>4chan</category><category>hackerone</category><category>responsible disclosure</category><category>hacking</category></item><item><title>Concerning a recent intrusion</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week we were made aware of a software vulnerability that allowed an intruder access to administrative functions and information from one of our databases. The intruder later stated their motive was to expose the posting habits of a specific user they disliked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After careful review, we believe the intrusion was limited to imageboard moderation panels, our reports queue, and some tables in our backend database. Due to the way the intruder extracted information from the database, we have detailed logs of what was accessed. The logs indicate that primarily moderator account names and credentials were targeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three 4chan Pass users had their Pass credentials accessed, and were notified and offered refunds and lifetime Passes shortly after the discovery. As a reminder, all payment information is processed securely by Stripe—we never see nor store any of it, and thus no payment information was compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We patched the vulnerability quickly after it came to our attention, and have spent—and will continue to spend—dozens of hours poring over our software and systems to help mitigate and prevent future intrusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re sorry it happened, and will do our best to ensure it doesn&amp;#8217;t happen again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/84289353232</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/84289353232</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 23:12:00 -0400</pubDate><category>4chan</category></item><item><title>Upcoming namespace changes</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In the coming week, we&amp;#8217;ll be making a few changes to how files are accessed. The changes are mostly cosmetic, and will be transparent to people using vanilla 4chan. We&amp;#8217;ll also continue to support legacy URLs for a short time to give third-party developers the opportunity to migrate their apps, but suggest making the appropriate updates as soon as possible to be prepared for when the changes go live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semantic thread URLs with slugs.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8220;res/&amp;#8221; will be renamed to &amp;#8220;thread/&amp;#8221;, and subject/comment snippets will be appended after the thread ID as a slug. For example, &amp;#8220;http(s)://boards.4chan.org/g/res/41321419&amp;#8221; would become &amp;#8220;http(s)://boards.4chan.org/g/thread/41321419/daily-programming-thread&amp;#8221;. This will be included in the JSON as the &amp;#8220;semantic_url&amp;#8221; attribute in the OP container.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less redundant file URLs.&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;#8220;src/&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;thumb/&amp;#8221; directories will be removed from images/thumbs.4chan.org and i/t.4cdn.org. Files will live at the board root on those subdomains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pages renumbered.&lt;/strong&gt; The board index will now start from &amp;#8220;Page 1&amp;#8221; instead of &amp;#8220;Page 0&amp;#8221;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/4chan/4chan-API" title="4chan API" target="_blank"&gt;4chan API&lt;/a&gt; documentation will be updated shortly before the changes go live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; To clarify, links that omit the slug and contain just the thread ID will continue to work as before, and slugs will only be in the URL bar and not post (&amp;#187;123) links. This change shouldn&amp;#8217;t affect you unless you constantly copy and paste URLs, or stare at your URL bar all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/82477681005</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/82477681005</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 09:52:00 -0400</pubDate><category>4chan</category></item><item><title>Goodbye to some old friends</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we &lt;a href="http://blog.4chan.org/post/81891220996/reintroducing-the-4chan-blog-and-blotter" title="Reintroducing the 4chan blog and blotter" target="_blank"&gt;welcomed two old features&lt;/a&gt; back to the site—the 4chan Blog and &lt;a href="//www.4chan.org/blotter" title="4chan Blotter" target="_blank"&gt;Blotter&lt;/a&gt;—but today we&amp;#8217;ll also say goodbye to a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past 10 years, 4chan has accumulated many features and side-projects, but since the team has rarely consisted of more than myself, a single volunteer developer, and a handful of volunteer moderators, many have been neglected. Specifically the discussion boards (dis.4chan.org) and Fileshares board (rs.4chan.org).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Rather than continue to neglect these side-projects, we&amp;#8217;ve decided to retire them so that we can focus our time and energy into maintaining and improving the core of the site—4chan&amp;#8217;s image boards.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The discussion boards will continue to live on in a read-only state, while the Fileshares board will be shut down. Both will be frozen and de-linked soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For the VIPPERs and &amp;#8220;expert programmers&amp;#8221; among us this may be a sad day, however we hope to accommodate you with some future image board features. Stay tuned.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/81998248943</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/81998248943</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 11:49:00 -0400</pubDate><category>4chan</category></item><item><title>WebM support on 4chan</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Today we added support for &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebM" title="WebM - Wikipedia" target="_blank"&gt;WebM&lt;/a&gt; files on 4chan&amp;#8217;s image boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While WebM is technically a video file format, it offers many advantages over animated GIFs—namely superior image quality, support for more than 256 colors, and reduced file size. Its main disadvantage is &lt;a href="http://caniuse.com/webm" title="Can I use the WebM/VP8 video format?" target="_blank"&gt;browser compatibility&lt;/a&gt;, however&lt;span&gt; 86% of 4chan&amp;#8217;s visits come from browsers that include full or partial support for WebM, and plug-ins are available for those that don&amp;#8217;t (like &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://tools.google.com/dlpage/webmmf/" title="WebM for Internet Explorer" target="_blank"&gt;Internet Explorer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.perian.org/" title="Perian for Mac OS X" target="_blank"&gt;Safari&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We decided to disallow WebM files with sound for a few reasons, but mainly because it&amp;#8217;s our intention to provide the site with better animated images, and not true video support. To that end, we only accept WebM files with one video stream and no audio streams, that are shorter than 120 seconds long, no larger than 2048x2048 pixels, and less than 3&amp;#160;MB in size.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re eager to see how 4chan&amp;#8217;s users will adopt WebM, and have posted &lt;strike&gt;this short guide&lt;/strike&gt; on encoding them to ease adoption. Many thanks to desuwa for both championing and implementing this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/81896300203</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/81896300203</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 12:51:00 -0400</pubDate><category>4chan</category><category>webm</category></item><item><title>Reintroducing the 4chan Blog and Blotter</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Long-time users will remember the late 4chan DevBlog and Blotter, which were removed almost five years ago due to infrequent use. We had used them to share updates with the community that didn&amp;#8217;t require lengthy news posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;#8217;m pleased to reintroduce both. As someone who &lt;a href="http://chrishateswriting.com/" title="moot on Tumblr" target="_blank"&gt;hates writing&lt;/a&gt; and prefers to publish &lt;a href="https://www.4chan.org/news" title="4chan - News" target="_blank"&gt;news posts&lt;/a&gt; only when absolutely necessary, I welcome their return. We&amp;#8217;ll continue to use the global message (big red text at the top of boards) to communicate important notices, but will use the blog and blotter to share a running tally of smaller updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may not realize it, but we&amp;#8217;re constantly working behind the scenes to improve the site—be it feature additions, code tweaks, or improving moderation. It&amp;#8217;s our hope to give the community more visibility into those improvements via a changelog of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href="https://www.tumblr.com/follow/4chan" title="Follow 4chan on Tumblr" target="_blank"&gt;give us a follow&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://blog.4chan.org/rss" title="Subscribe to 4chan Blog via RSS" target="_blank"&gt;subscribe via RSS&lt;/a&gt;, and keep an eye on the &lt;a href="//www.4chan.org/blotter" title="4chan Blotter" target="_blank"&gt;blotter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—moot&lt;a href="http://chrishateswriting.com" title="moot on Tumblr" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.4chan.org/post/81891220996</link><guid>http://blog.4chan.org/post/81891220996</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 11:56:00 -0400</pubDate><category>4chan</category></item></channel></rss>
